现在我们要进入 Docker 的一些功能
So now we're gonna go into
some features in Docker, and
我要把你的门展示给不同的路径
I'm gonna just show you the door
down to multiple different pathways.
欢迎你加入，你可以更深入地了解这些话题，对吧 ?
And you're welcome to peek in and you
can go deeper into these topics, right?
比如说，连网，那是一个真正的深坑洞洞，再一次，
Like, for example, networking, that's
a real deep rabbit hole that, again,
我没资格跟你说
I'm not particularly qualified
to talk to you about.
但我要向你们展示如何做基本的网络和
But I'm just gonna show you how to
do the basics of networking and
然后你就可以从那里学到更多的东西
then from there you can go and
learn more about it.
所以第一个是比较类似的话题，绑架，
So the first one is, these are relatively
similar topics, bind mounts and
卷，但结果相对不同，我们一起去吧。
volumes, but they accomplish relatively
different results, let's go with.
这个想法是你在运行之间有某种持久的存储，对吧 ?
The idea is that you have some sort of
persistent storage between runs, right?
所以如果我有这个容器它会有一堆东西
So if I have this container and
it does a bunch of stuff and
然后输出到该绑定安装或卷，以及
then outputs it to this bind mount or
volume, and
那我再去那个集装箱，那个国家还会在，对吧 ?
then I go run that container again,
that state will still be there, right?
我们需要某种方式在运行之间保持这种状态
We need some way that we can have
this state maintained between runs
集装箱对吧
of containers, right?
当容器关闭时，它们会将之前的所有内容都删除，对吗 ?
Cuz when containers get closed, they drop
everything that they had before, right?
到目前为止，我们一直在处理自己所包含的容器。
So, so far, we've been dealing
with self contained containers.
所以，这通常是你想要的，只是一个容器
So, this is normally like this is all you
ever want, is just a container that is
完全的自我控制了，做点什么，就会消失，对吧 ?
totally self contained, that runs,
does something and disappears, right?
一个重要的关键是我们不想要我们称之为雪花的东西。
And a big key about this is that we do
not wanna have what we call snowflakes.
雪花就像一些你跑出来的特殊服务器
A snowflake is like some special
server that you have out running
在生产服务器上。
on your production servers.
你刚刚对它进行了按摩，就像这个扫把的手工服务器
And you've just massaged it and it's
like this bespoke artisanal server that
都有正确的版本和一切正常的工作
has all the proper versions and
everything's working correctly.
如果它消失了，你的整个系统就会下降，对吗 ?
If it just goes away,
your entire system can come down, right?
如果发生这种情况会发生什么，对吗 ?
And what happens if that happens, right?
那你就得回去了，要重新创造各种不同的
Then you have to go back and you have to
go recreate all those various different
想知道你是怎么到那里的
sets to figure out how you got there.
这很有问题，对，
And that's problematic, right,
因为我们不想这样做对吧
because we don't want that
necessarily to happen, right?
我们不想被这个扫雪的服务子所征服
We don't wanna be subjugated to
this bespoke, snowflake service.
这就是为什么容器很棒因为你可以把它们旋起来
So that's why containers are great,
because you can spin them up and
你可以把他们关起来你可以把他们关起来然后把他们关起来
you can close them down, you can spin
them up and you can close them down,
就像这里的集装箱的吸引力
and that's kind of like
the appeal here of containers.
所以我们在努力避免雪花
So we're trying to avoid snowflakes.
有类似的想法
There's the idea of like,
你不想要雪花而你想要的是什么人叫牛对吧
you don't want snowflakes and
you want what people call cattle, right?
我对上帝发誓这不是我的比喻
And I swear to God, this is not my
analogy, but the idea is that you have
很多牛和一头牛都没有别的牛，对吧 ?
many cattle and one cow is not any
different than the other cow, right?
所以你就是想把一切都一模一样你就可以换掉了
So you just wanna have everything is just
exactly the same and you can swap them out
你可以取代他们一切都很好
and you can replace them and
everything else, and that's just fine.
我不会再做这个比喻了，但这就是人们说的，好吗 ?
I will go no further into that metaphor,
but that's what people say, okay?
但并非所有东西都能整齐地装进一个容器里
However, not everything can fit neatly
into a container all the time and
这个数据库是一个很好的例子，对吧 ?
a really good example of
this is databases, right?
所以我可以上下旋转 SQL 数据库，对吧 ?
So I can spin up and
down my SQL databases, right?
而且我有各种不同的客户
And it's fine that I have
various different clients or
服务器对吧
servers of that right?
但核心数据需要保留在运行之间，对吗 ?
But the core data needs to be
preserved between runs, right?
所以如果我放大我的数据库，我有 100 个容器在运行，那么我就会缩小
So if I scale up my database and I have
100 containers running, then I scale down
十，我不想丢失那个数据，那是重要的部分，对吧 ?
to 10, I don't wanna lose that data,
that's the important part, right?
这就是为什么我们会被称为装配的东西，对吧 ?
So that's why we're gonna get
into things called mounts, right?
而我们今天将要讨论的两个不同的火种
And the two different kinda mounts
that we're gonna talk about today, and
我认为有四种或五种不同的类型。
I think there's four or
five different types.
但两个主要的，有用的将是绑定安装和卷安装。
But the two primary, useful ones are going
to be bind mounts and volume mounts.
那么，绑定安装类似于主机计算机的门户网站，对吗 ?
So bind mounts are like portals
to your host computer, right?
所以我可以说，好吧，这里是一个文件夹，
So I can say, okay,
here's this folder, and
这个集装箱就能看到这个文件夹，对吧 ?
this container can see just this folder,
right?
我们会把它安装在这个特定的地方，它会被捆绑，对吗 ?
And we're gonna mount it in this one
particular place and it's bound, right?
任何容器更改都显示在主机上的任何信息，
So anything that container changes
shows up on the host computer,
任何电脑的改变都在容器里结束对吧
anything the host computer changes
ends up in the container, right?
他们被捆绑在一起好吗
They're bound together, okay?
这对像开发容器之类的东西真的有用，对吧 ?
This can be really useful for
things like developer containers, right?
因此，如果我是编写代码，它需要在特定 kinda 容器中执行，或者
So, if I'm writing code, it needs to
execute in a specific kinda container or
环境，这真的很有用，对吧 ?
environment, this is really useful for
that, right?
例如，我的计算机上没有安装 " Go " ，但是
Like for example, I don't have
a Go installed in my computer, but
如果我想开发一个 Go 项目或者运行一个 Go 项目，对，
if I wanted to develop a Go project or
run a Go project, right,
我可以用一个容器
I could do that with a container.
然后使用绑定安装，以便在任何时候修改代码，
And then use a bind mount so
that anytime I modify the code,
对容器内部的密码进行修改。
it modifies the code
inside of the container.
因此，绑定安装将是有用的。
So that's where bind mounts
are gonna be useful.
我要教你怎么做这个特别的
So, I'm gonna show you how to do this
really quickly here with this particular
就在这里你可以从我的笔记中直接复制和粘贴
command right here, which you can copy and
paste directly off of my notes here.
所以说清楚
So let's clear.
所以我再次进入了我的静态资产项目
So I'm inside of my, again,
static-assets-project,
你刚刚建的那个是吧
the one that you just built, right?
我要做船坞跑架就在这里
And I'm gonna do docker run -- mount,
right here, right,
然后我会打打打捆
and then I would do a type= bind.
因此，这是一个绑定安装，而不是卷安装。
So this is a bind mount,
not a volume mount.
你得说这个消息来源就是这个
You're gonna say, the source and
this is this pwd,
你得给它一条完整的路径一条绝对的路径
you have to give it a full path,
an absolute path as it's called, right?
我不想把它全部输入出来所以你可以在这里玩这个
And I don't wanna type out all of it,
so you can do this trick right here,
就是 "$(pwd)" 就像我现在的输出，就是这样。
which is "$(pwd)" is like output where
I am right now, that's what this does.
或者如果你想这么做你就可以把这条合格的路
Or you could just put the whole
qualified path if you wanna do that,
/build，是我已经造出来的，对吧 ?
/build, which is the part that
I already built out, right?
然后目标，这就是我想让它在容器里输出的地方，对吧 ?
And then target, this is where I want it
to output within the container, right?
所以，此输出到 usr/share/nginx/html，这应该是
So this outputs to
the usr/share/nginx/html, that should look
熟悉你的情况，对，因为那就是我们输出这个建筑过程的地方。
familiar to you, right, because that's
where we output the build process.
然后我们在 8080 端口发布我们要运行 nginx
And then we're publishing on port 8080,
and we're gonna run nginx,
我们把它放进 1.17 号好吗 ?
and let's just put in 1.17 so that we can
be running on a consistent version, okay?
那么你希望现在发生什么呢 ?
So what do you expect to happen now?
我要直接把那只金花容器直接跑了
I'm actually gonna be running
the nginx container directly, right,
我没有在上面建任何东西
I'm not building anything on top of it.
但我们要完成同样的事
But we're gonna accomplish the same thing,
right,
还会以同样的方式工作
it's still gonna work the exact same way.
那么现在我们做了这个，这个开始，现在还可以到 8080 ，对吧 ?
So now that we've done that, this starts
up and now we can still go to 8080, right?
所以 8080 ，看，还在跑，对吧 ?
So 8080, and look,
it's still running, right?
它直接从 nginx 跑了不是从我们的容器里跑来的
It's running directly from nginx,
it's not running from our built container,
是从 nginx 跑的对吧
it's running from nginx, right?
但是我们用装订架从我们的档案中
But we used a bind mount to mount
basically a portal from our file
并将其放入 nginx中
system here and putting that into nginx.
所以我们会做更多的例子
So, we'll do more examples of this, but
就像绑定安装的基础
that's like the base of
what bind mounts are.
所以这直接从我的 Mac 电脑里装进了这个容器。
So this is really directly out of my Mac
to serve this up into the container.
有道理吗
Does it make sense?
>> 构建文件夹不在容器中，
&gt;&gt; The build folder is
not in the container,
就像普通的文件夹一样，而容器实际上是 nginx。
it's just sitting like regular folder,
and then the container's actually nginx.
就像，好吧，我去拿那个静态文件夹，我要去做。
It's like, okay, I'm gonna go grab that
static folder, I'm gonna serve it.
>> Right， cutz I 基本上是在我的 Mac 和容器内部
&gt;&gt; Right, cuz I basically tunneled between
my Mac and the inside of the container.
>> 没有涉及 Docker 文件。
&gt;&gt; There's no Docker file involved.
>> 没有其他 Docker 文件涉及，正确，是的，我们只是
&gt;&gt; There's no additional Docker file
involved, correct, yeah, we're just
直接在 Docker 集线器上运行 nginx 容器时不进行任何更改。
running the nginx container directly
off the Docker hub with no changes.
魔术
Magic.
所以这才是束缚装的作用
So that's what bind
mounts can be useful for
我们能装到那样的东西对吧
is we can mount in stuff like that, right?
现在，我是否要在生产中做到这一点还是要构建自己的容器?
Now, would I do this in production
versus building my own container?
不我还是要建一个集装箱因为如果我建那个集装箱，
No, I would still build a container
because if I build that container,
完全是自我控制的我可以把它扔在任何地方
it's totally self contained,
I can throw it anywhere.
我能把它放在 Azure 上我可以放在 AWS上
I can put it on Azure,
I can put it on AWS,
我可以说执行那个集装箱
I can say just execute that container.
我不需要再多设置它只会运行容器
I don't have to set it up any more than
that, it just runs the container and
都是有用的对吧
it just works, right?
但如果我能做到这一点我就得明白了
Whereas if I try and accomplish this, I
have to like, okay, well, bind mount this,
这就是这里你要从这个地方读
this, this is here and
you have to read from this place and
一堆类似的东西
a bunch of stuff like that.
用我们以前的术语来说更有一点雪
It's a bit more snowflaky for that,
to use our previous terminology.
所以，这确实是有道理的，这就能理解约束卷在做什么，对吗 ?
So, does that makes sense, that makes
sense what bind volumes are doing, right?
因此，这对于像开发环境这样的东西来说是非常有用的。
So again, this is quite useful for
things like development environments.
那是我最后要说的
And that was the last
thing I was gonna mention,
您可以将该文件安装到 etsy， nginx和nginx.conf。
is you can mount that file to etsy,
nginx, nginx.conf.
如果要修改配置，那么可以使用另一个绑定安装
If you wanna modify the configuration,
you could use another bind mount
修改 nginx 的配置，这将完全正常工作。
to modify the configuration of nginx and
that would totally work as well.
对于操作系统，就像容器一样，它无法分辨
To the operating system, like to the
container, it cannot tell the difference
在绑定程序和普通文件之间有问题吧
between a bind mount and
just normal files there, right?
它只显示在那个容器上，就像它通常安装在那个文件中一样
It just shows up to that container as if
it was normally mounted into that file
系统很酷
system, which is pretty cool.
所以我想，你们中的很多人已经开始了新的发展工作
So again, I imagine many of you have
started at new development jobs and
当你第一步走的时候他们会给你看一个可能
when you walk in the first thing they do
is they hand you a read me that's probably
大约 6 个月的时间对吧
about six months out of date, right?
然后你就得走了
And then you have to go and
了解如何逐步建立这一发展环境，
figure out how to set up this development
environment step by step and things break,
你得去问高级开发人员，我该怎么做呢 ?
and you have to go ask the senior
developer, how do I do this?
就像这样做对吧
It's like, fine, do this, right?
或者没人知道，那是更糟的事情，对吧 ?
Or no one knows,
that's the even worse thing, right?
我去过那里我想你们很多人都在那儿
I've been there,
I imagine many of you have been there.
这就是捆绑架和容器可以聚集在一起的地方
So that's where bind mounts and
containers can come together and
对你很有用吧
be very useful to you, right?
因为他们可以给你一个容器
Because they can just hand
you a container, so like,
在此，此容器具有您需要启动的所有内容。
here, this container has everything
that you need to get started.
只需将代码绑定到该特定区域，例如运行容器，以及
Just bind mount your code into this
particular area, say run container, and
你有一个已经为你建立的这个发展环境。
you have this development environment that
someone else has already set up for you.
然后你就可以开始编解码了
And you can just start coding away and
it works on day one.
这就是发展环境对容器的承诺。
That's kinda the promise of development
environments with containers.
不是下一节，而是我们教你如何去做的。
And, not next section, but the section
after that we'll show you how to do that.